We all know what term insurance is, but the benefits keep
coming every day.
People like me keep
saying, "Take term insurance, take it." So many people are
saying that, and if you
start making inquiries, there
are 12 term insurance companies in the market.  Each company
has different plans, and if
we look at the total in India, there are
more than 50 plans.  Let's say you have chosen one of these 50
plans,
made an inquiry and
chosen a plan.
After that, how much coverage should you have? 50
lakh quota, two crores, three crores. Many
people are not clear about it. Let's say you have put in a crore.
Then, the term means
how many years you want coverage. Until you
reach 60 years, until you reach 80 years,
until you reach 99 years. How much
term should you choose? Many
people are also not clear about this.
For example, let's say you save until you reach age 60
.  You
are taking it offline.  Your insurance
agent will ask, "Sir, do you need riders? I have a
good rider and would you like me to add it?"
We don't have clarity on what riders actually mean and which rider should be added.   For
example, let's say that one
rider was added by him.  Now the
main thing is that the premium is your annual premium and
he says, "We'll
be shocked, but reduce everything a little bit." I do
n't know what he'll do. Even if the coverage is the same and the term is the same, he'll still
reduce the premium.  This reduction will
bring many changes to our plan.
What are the chances of changes? If
you have all these doubts,
I will give you full clarity in this video.
How much coverage should you put in? How much age should you
put in?
What kind of riders should you add? The main thing is
how to choose a good plan. I will explain all this pin to
pin in this video.
So watch this video till the end.
Also, if you have not subscribed to this channel till now,
subscribe now. I am your Kaushik and I am the
first one. How much coverage should you put in? The
mistake that many people make here is that they
blindly put in crores of rupees of coverage
.  If
you ask them why they paid a crore for coverage, the answer they give is that everyone is
paying a crore.  That's why
I also have coverage of one crore rupees, they
say.  What is actual coverage
?  If we are at risk after taking this policy, the
insurance company will
deposit the amount of coverage we choose into the family bank account.  If we
don't, that crore rupees
will go to our family.  Don't blindly invest a crore.   There
is a formula for this, it may change, it
may be different for me, it may be different for you.  The
coverage we take may change according to this formula
.  What is that formula?  Basically, if you
ask me 15 to 20 times how much you earn per year, I will tell you to take 20 20 times. For
example, you earn
12 lakhs per year. You are the only one in
your family. Your family
expenses are almost the same. Let's say that
12 lakhs is enough, including investments.
So 12* 20 is
2.4cr, 4cr, 2 crores, 40 lakhs. It is
better if you have coverage. Wait, wait, there is more. Suppose
you have loans by mistake. You need to
add those loans to this 2.4cr. For
example, you have a loan of 30 lakhs.  So
add these 30 lakhs to 2.4 4 crores
and there is another future goals. You have
a goal of your own. You have a baby. You want to
make the baby's wedding grand. Let's say
that is your goal. So it will
cost you 25 lakhs.
Let's make the wedding a little better, it will
cost 25 lakhs.  Add that expense too. If
we don't have to go tomorrow, the wedding has to go as
planned. If it goes as planned,
money has to go, right? 25 lakhs. So
add that money too.  So,
subtract one from this. What
investments do you already have? You have already invested
well in mutual funds here and there.
How much did you do?
Make 15 lakhs. Minus that 15 lakhs. If
you have coverage as much as you get, it would be
good. So, if you look at your example,
12 lakhs of income. So
even if we are not there, 20 years of income should
go to them. So, 12* 20 is 2.4 4 crores.
Add 30 lakhs to that. And your goal is to get married.
Add 25 lakhs. From that,
subtract 15 lakhs. If you calculate everything, it will be
2.8 crores. 8 crores. So, if your
coverage is 2 crores. 8 crores. It would be good.
See
how much loss you would have incurred if you had blindly taken a coverage of one crore rupees.
And there is inflation here. You should also
keep that in mind. There is
inflation, that is why I said 20 times
today is one crore rupees.  It is
not equal to one crore rupees in the future, its value will
definitely decrease, that's why I said 20 times, do you
understand? So, if you are the one who should fix your coverage like this, let
us know. All
this is not because of us. If you want to
talk to an expert, there
is a Ditto Ditto platform. If you want, the link is given in the
description below in the comments.
So if we click on that link,
give basic information and click on request call back, an
IRDAI certified expert
will call you immediately. So we can say, I want to take a
term plan, how much
coverage should I have? Ask all these questions, ask every
doubt, do you
understand that they will give you clarification if you have anything? So, if they are not, they
will not call you.  This means that the call will only be made when you
click on Request Call Back
.  So, as
IRDAI certified advisors,
ask and clarify all your doubts
.  If you want, they will
suggest a good plan.  If
you take it from them,
they will help you in times of crisis in the future
.  Do you understand? So if you
want, click on the link and
enter basic information and type in Telugu Advisor.
There, it says that Telugu
people will call you. And
they have a 4.9 9 star rating and
it is backed by zero. Okay, let's
go directly to the topic. Next, one
second doubt, how much term should be kept?
Some people keep the term until they reach the age of 99
.  If you ask me, there's no
need for that.  Save until your financial
responsibilities end
.  That means, invest for as long as your
family can depend on you financially
.  For example, you're 30,
you have a baby and a baby for two years, and you've been
planning to have one
.  So you are working
.  You will retire when you turn 60
.  There are
many retirement benefits after retirement.  And
pension also comes from EPFO.   This
means that after 60 years, you will receive
money as a lump sum.  So, if your present age is 30,
you have opted for a 30-year term,
which means you will have
this coverage until you reach the age of 60.  If
you take a risk before 60, that money will
go.  So, even if you are alive at 60, why do
n't you get money? Why is it
better to save until 60? You will
get a lot of retirement money at 60.  So your
wife won't be so dependent either.  You can
spend time with that money and have children.
Now, you are 30, your father's
age will be 32 when you turn 60
.  He will have settled for 32.  He is either working or doing
business.
His life is his own, so he is
not financially dependent on you. Even if it is
risky after 60, he will have retirement
money, so your wife is
not financially dependent either.  So there is
no dependency, so there is
no point in using term insurance.  So what some people
do is they save until they reach the age of 99
.  Your son is on his feet, your
wife also
has retirement money,
why else would we take it until we reach the age of 99?  We assume that if I'm
not there, my people won't be on the road
.  So I think it's enough till 60
and now the main thing is
how to choose a good insurance plan. The
first thing you need to check for a term insurance plan is the client
settlement ratio. At any time, the
client settlement ratio of that company should be
more than 95%.  If you
ask me, there are many companies with client settlement ratios like 98, 99, and
I think it would be better to take one of them
.  For example, if a company
has a claim settlement ratio of 99%, that
means that if 100 claims are received, for example, 100 claims are received, and out
of 100 claims, 99
claims are given. If that company
rejects only one claim and gives 99 claims, then
that company's claim
settlement ratio is 99%,
not only the claim settlement ratio. What
you need to look at is the amount settlement
ratio. This amount settlement
ratio should be more than 90%. Do you understand? Don't
blindly take it by saying that the client settlement ratio is good. This
amount settlement ratio should also definitely be
more than 90%.
What is the actual amount settlement ratio?  A claim of 100 crores has been received
.  Many people applied for the claim
.  100 crore claim.  The amount settlement ratio is
how many crores of this 100 crore rupees
the company paid in the claim form
.  For example, let's say you
settled 90 crores out of a claim of
100 crores. Overall, out of a claim of 100 crores, you
settled 90 crores and
only withheld 10 crores.
Otherwise, you rejected it.
In that case, the company's amount
settlement ratio is 90%, so before taking it,
check whether it is 90% or not.  Next
Solvency Ratio The solvency ratio of that company should be
more than 150%
.  Check that too.
How to check all this? If you think of a company,
type it in Google and
all the information will come up. What is the actual
solvency ratio of a certain company?
Type in the solvency ratio of a certain company. Suppose it is 160%. It is
fine because it should be 150 plus and should not
be less than 150. When you
check, it should be 100. It is a bit risky
so the solvency ratio should be more than 150%. If you are a company,
check that too.
And lastly,
when do complaints come? When do complaints come to a company? If they
apply to the Climat and
do not get that claim, they will
file a complaint with IRDAI. Who are the customers? Those
complaints should be few.  So for every
10,000 claims, there should be
less than 20 complaints.  Suppose a company receives
more than 20
complaints for every 10,000 claims. This means that the
company is not processing claims properly,
otherwise it will delay or
reject them.  So check that
the complaints should be
less than 20 for every 10,000 claims.
Check all these and then take it only. Don't
take it blindly. Next One Riders.
What is the real rider? Rider means extra
benefit.
Extra benefit rider comes to your basic plan. So how many
riders are there? If you look in the market, there are many riders. Do you
need all the riders? If you
ask me, is it better to take this as a major?
What is Waiver of Premium? For
example, in the future, there is an
accident, an accident and disability, that is, the
legs and hands are
numb. We are not at the stage where we work. We are
just lying on the bed or
lying on the wheelchair. In such a situation, if
you have taken this rider in advance,
we do not need to pay the rest of the premiums. For
example, you have taken a 30-year
term and after completing 15 years, an
accident occurs.  So I'm
lying in a wheelchair and can't work.   There is no
income, the rest of the
premiums, that is, the
company will pay every premium for the next 15 years,
we don't need to pay.  And in the same
way, cancer comes. For example, we get
cancer and are lying in bed.   Even then, we won't be able to
work, so even then,
we don't have to pay the rest of the premiums,
that's what the Waiver of
Premium Rider is.  Adding this rider
will increase the premium slightly.   This
means that the premium we have to pay will
increase slightly every month.  It's good to take this,
and many of us have driving
jobs or would otherwise continue to travel every day
on our bikes or cars.   It would be
better for such people to take the accidental death benefit.  You will be working as a driver
.  That's why this rider was added
.
We should also check the coverage for this rider at the time of adding it
.  So
you have chosen 50 lakhs of coverage for the accidental death benefit writer
.  So, take a look and
tie it for a few years.  After that, if there is a
risk due to an accident,
our family should get a quote, not a crore, but a normal one
.  But since you
added this rider, you will get an
extra 50 lakhs if you die in an accident
.  So, the base premium rider and
all together, Rs. 50 lakhs
will go to our family.  Do you understand that this rider benefit is
something that we have to pay a little extra money for,
and
if we want a critical illness rider, we can add it.
This is set for people like our
grandparents, our grandmothers, our great-grandmothers,
they all had illnesses, they all had cancer,
or they all died of heart attacks
.  There are cases like this,
so there is a chance that some of them will be inherited by us
.  If you are in such a situation,
this critical illness
rider will be set for you.  So some
companies say that if you
take this rider, you will get 50 critical illnesses,
which means that if you get
any of these illnesses and you are
bedridden, you will get the coverage you need, and the amount of
coverage you need for this rider will be
deposited in your bank account while you are alive. Do you understand that some companies
only give 20 critical illnesses, which
means they only cover 20 illnesses?
For example, you are
taking a plan.  Suppose you feel that there is a
chance of inheriting a disease and
you take out a critical illness writer
. The basic coverage is normally Rs. 1 crore.  You said 25 locks as an example of
how much coverage you will be asked at the time of collection
.  If you get sick with any of those illnesses and are
bedridden,
that money will be
deposited into our bank account while you are still alive.
Do you understand the same thing as the critical illness rider?  So these are
enough, if you
want to check it out depending on your situation, and another
question is, if we take the policy at the time of taking it, if there is a
risk for you in the future, should you give the amount of coverage to your family at
once, or if not, should you not give it at once, but should you give some
money at
once and deposit the remaining amount in the form of this girl, that is, this much per month, in their bank account? If not, should you give some money at once and deposit the remaining amount in the
form of this girl, that is, this much per month,
in their bank account?
So you like it,
you can check it out. Do you have a doubt? Suppose my
son Dolagad mistakenly deposited one or two crores in the
account. Do you have a doubt that he will pay the expenses? If
you want,
you can put this much per month for their expenses. It
doesn't matter.
Suppose a two-tier coverage
falls to one crore rupees and the remaining one crore
rupees does not fall at once.
You can set it up to be paid monthly, so if you
ask me, if they
know financial planning well, it's
better to take it all at once.
There are many schemes that provide monthly interest even if you deposit one crore rupees in a bank account and invest another crore rupees.  So if they are in the
right mind and are smart enough to do it all
at once, it would be
better.  And before taking the policy,
mention everything clearly, whether you are taking it
online or
offline,
check everything 10 times and
enter it. Write your name well, date
of birth, everything is correct, if you have to
give it, if there is any mistake, you will not get a claim in the
future. I think
you liked this information. If you like it,
say you liked it. If you don't like it, say you didn't like it. At the end of
the day, I want you to take it in a good company. I
want you to get a claim. That's it. Nothing more.
We see many people. Unfortunately, if the
head of the family dies, the whole family has to go
on the road. For
many people, I don't want that situation to happen to our families
.  So if you like it, tell me you like it.
If you have any doubts,
ask below. I will come back with another video
and if you want to talk to an expert before taking it, it is
completely free. I
am saying it is
completely free. I have given the link.
Click on it and give me all the information and
schedule a call. They will call you
back. Thank you so much
for watching. Jai Hind
Boss Wala Be the Boss.